Guide to the Samuel Shaffer papers, 1948-1982 MS2091
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Book typescript, undated; MS2091 Series 3; 2 Linear feet
  This series contains two early typescripts of "On and Off the Floor" (the second one has heavy manuscript annotations), inserts and revisions, a retyped typescript of the book, and the author's galleys of the book. "On and Off the Floor" is based on Shaffer's Newsweek submissions. The book, dedicated to the memory of his wife, is Shaffer's reminiscences of political personalities and events from McCartyism to Richard Nixon's abdication of the presidency.
  - Early Typescript, Chapters 1-6, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Early Typescript, Chapters 7-12, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Early Typescript, Chapters 13 - 16 & Epilogue, On and the Floor, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Book typescript, undated (Box 36)
  - Early Typescript, With Heavy Manuscript Annotations, Chapters 1 - 8, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Early Typescript, With Heavy Manuscript Annotations, Chapter 9 - 14, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Early Typescript, With Heavy Manuscript Annotations, Chapters 15 - 17 & Epilogue, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Book typescript, undated (Box 37)
  - Inserts and Revisions, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Retyped Typescript, Chapters 1-6, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Retyped Typescript, Chapters 7-12, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Retyped Typescript, Chapters 13 -17 & Epilogue, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Book typescript, undated (Box 38)
  - Author's Galleys, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Author's Galleys, On and Off the Floor, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)